# Sajid Ali



Flat 4, 21 Andover Street, Leicester LE2 0JA

+44 746 6266438

x ali.sajid@yahoo.com

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Expert network administrator and with 10+ years' experience both private and international organizations, seeking to leverage proven Cisco skills. Managed servers in a Windows 2012 system with 99% up-time. Improved network performance via monitoring and application prioritization. Designed, and implementation of wired and wireless connectivity across different campuses.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 01/03/2018-Present

# General Manager of Sunset Resort

Sunset Resort, Islamabad (Pakistan)

- In-charge IT
- Digital marketing and social media management
- Bookings Management
- Finance Logs
- Quality Management of resort

#### 01/09/2013-Present

### Freelance work - IT-technical support

Islamabad (Pakistan)

- Technical support & troubleshooting of hardware & computers
- Installation and troubleshooting of Windows/ MAC
- Troubleshooting of OS and softwares
- Providing network and wireless solutions
- Social media management
- Website and email server solutions

#### 01/09/2007-30/12/2010

# System Support Administrator

International School of Islamabad, Islamabad (Pakistan)

- Assist with management for IT hardware, software and infrastructure, functionality and operations of the MIS system, necessary upgrades, backup and support for the school's MIS systems.
- Assist with maintenance of an accurate inventory of technology resources, providing maximum use
  of equipment for school's goals.
- Maximize the educational support offered to classroom teachers by the technology staff.
- Advise departments in the design and implementation of new information systems and provide necessary upgrades, backup and support.
- In conjunction with administrators, faculty and staff, evaluate school information technology needs and set priorities for meeting those needs within budgeting constraints.
- Manage Organization's Microsoft server infrastructure ensuring 100% up-time
- Troubleshoots problems with networks, web services, mail services
- Provides day-to-day desktop support for end-users as well as support for remote users
- Monitor system logs and activity on all servers and devices
- Troubleshoots and sets up workstations, maintain and add to existing cabling infrastructure
- Service calls for Printers/Copiers/fax and supplies
- Train Network users, answer questions, resolve problems and communicate changes in software / operations.

- Install, and maintain configure and test hardware and software desktop/laptop and server products as necessary to provide services to customers, internal and external.
- Upgrade desktop/laptop and server environment, including working with users for a smooth transition.
- Monitor the operation of the desktop/laptop and server environment, including audit trail review, backup dumps, and security advisories, and take actions as necessary.
- Develop operational procedures for desktop/laptop and server systems, permitting operations staff to maintain these services on a routine basis.

#### 01/06/2002-31/08/2007

# In-charge Servers & LAN/WAN

COMSATS University Islamabad (formally known as COMSATS Institute of Information Technology), Islamabad (Pakistan)

- Installation and configuration of Linux 9.0 based E-mail Server.
- Setup and maintenance of Squid and Windows ISA Server.
- Working on Windows 2000 based Domain Servers and its Backup Servers.
- Create and maintain user's accounts, profiles and E-Mail of more than 5000 users.
- Responsible for smooth running of 4Mbps Internet bandwidth
- Exchange Server 2003, Students Telnet Server, and FTP Servers
- Experience of implementation and work on the SQL and Oracle server
- Also established the intranet and internet of sub campuses and offices.
- Responsible for smooth running, monitoring of entire network and Servers of COMSATS and its various campuses.
- Hands on Cisco Routers 1700, 2500, 2600, 3800 and manageable switches.
- Configuration and maintenance of PRTG, MRTG in Linux and windows.
- Experience of Fibreoptic, VSAT, ISDN, DSL, ADSL, Radio Link, Dialup Modems.
- Management of APC UPS RT 3000, 2200, 1100 with the help of power chute.
- Installation and maintenance of Printers HP Ink jet and Leaser jet series.

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# 01/10/2011-30/06/2013

# Master of Computer Engineering & IT in Quality Management

EQF level 7

Lucian Blaga University of Sibiu, Sibiu (Romania)

- Statistical process control
- Reliability and maintainability
- Experimental research & data processing
- Quality Tools
- Quality policies & institutional mechanics
- Human capital in organizations
- Total quality management
- Marketing management
- Operational health & safety management systems
- Optional courses: Information & communication techniques, Environment management, Audi & certification of quality systems

# 01/09/1999-01/07/2003

# **Bachelors of Computer Science**

EQF level 6

University of Punjab, Lahore (Pakistan)

Computer Science

### PERSONAL SKILLS

# Mother tongue(s)

Urdu, Punjabi

### Foreign language(s)

English

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C1	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### Communication skills

Good communication skills

### Organisational / managerial skills

- Strong attention to detail and customer-service orientation, as well as the ability to work on a team.
- Interpersonal skills and experience in presenting
- Problem solving and project management experience

#### Job-related skills

- Administering the operation of LAN/WAN-related network services according to company policies and procedures
- Coordinating and implementing network software and hardware upgrades
- Troubleshooting and resolving LAN/WAN performance, connectivity and related network problems
- Administering LAN/WAN security, antivirus and spam control measures
- Provide technical oversight of a multi-site enterprise level WAN, including planning, expansion/implementation, maintenance, and troubleshooting
- Budgeting for equipment and assembly costs
- Strong troubleshooting diagnostic and analytic skills, along with good communication skills.

# Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT					
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving	
Proficient user	Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user	Proficient user	

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### Certifications

- Certification of CCNA Course on ICND (Interconnecting Cisco Network Devices) Obtained 2<sup>nd</sup> position
- Linux

# References

Rose Puffer

Superintendent, International School of Islamabad Email: rpuffer@isoi.edu.pk

Dr. Muhammad Manzoor Ilahi Tamimy

Associate Professor, Department of Computer Science, COMSATS University Islamabad Park Road, Tarlai Kalan, Islamabad, 45550

Email: tamimy@comsats.edu.pk